Muhammad Naufal Pratama

mhnpratama@gmail.com · LinkedIn · Github · Medium · Web

A highly passionate engineer in the technology field with lots of software engineering experience, especially on the Back-end side, with the extra capability of Full-stack, DevOps, and Machine learning-related stuff.

EXPERIENCES

C++ Software Engineer Intern

Nodeflux

Internship August 2022 - December 2022

• Dealing against C++ in an internship as a C++ SWE intern at Nodeflux. Develop two surveillance camera analytic products (PPE detector & Person Re-identification) using Python and Docker, and also implement a dynamically loaded library in C++ for the final project, which is an image classification API.

• Tech: C++, Python, OpenCV, ONNX, Vegeta, Grafana, Prometheus, Docker & Postman

DevOps/SRE Intern

Fita

Internship

June 2022 - August 2022

- Having internship as a DevOps/SRE intern at Fita (Telkomsel's subsidiary) and Contributed to the GCP cloud armor setup and the Helm configuration, created a Terraform dependencies auto updater pipeline using Renovate to minimize the need for changing the dependencies version manually, and also set up a VictoriaMetrics alerting system to help warn the developers when there is a problem.
- Tech: GitLab CI/CD, GCP, Kubernetes, and Helm, Terraform, Grafana, & VictoriaMetrics

Backend Engineer Course

Generasi GIGIH 2.0

Studi Independen Kampus Merdeka Feb 2022 - July 2022

- Participate as a Backend Engineer and gain much insight into the Generasi GIGIH 2.0 program held by Yayasan Anak Bangsa Bisa (YABB) and developing a trash delivery system as the final project.
- Tech: Ruby, Ruby On Rails & Git

Fullstack Engineer Intern

Internship

UPT Perpustakaan UNDIP Feb 2022 - June 2022

- Worked eagerly as a full-stack engineer to develop an automated mail template platform for helping library staff write a formal letter without manually writing it through a word editor, but instead can write on it directly from the web and share the result.
- Tech: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PHP, Laravel, Redis, RabbitMQ, Git & Heroku

IEEE SB-Undip Organization

Web Division Committe

Universitas Diponegoro July 2021 - May 2022

- Initiate and manage IEEE SB-Undip website using WordPress and coordinate website development training the IWT (IEEE Website Training).
- Tech: WordPress

Software Defect Prediction Research

University Research

Universitas Diponegoro March 2021 - October 2021

- Research and explore in-depth about defects in software using machine learning and deep learning algorithms such as CNN, LSTM, and Random Forest from the experiments until the paper publications. Found out that a simple Random forest algorithm can handle this problem effectively.
- Tech: Python, Keras, NumPy, Git, Machine learning & Deep learning

Backend Engineer Mulo

Mulo, Wonosobo Feb 2021 - Aug 2022

Part-time Backend Engineer

- Contribute to both developing from scratch the backend API, using SailsJS and also the android app, using Kotlin for Mulo while also handle the documentation and software artefact. Mulo is a startup company that uses blockchain technology to empower UMKM in Indonesia by providing an application to help manage UMKM activities and finances.
- Tech: NodeJS, SailsJS, Kotlin, PostgreSQL, Insomnia, Git & Heroku

Backend Engineer Intern

Internship

Azura Labs, Semarang Jan 2021 - Mar 2021

- Develop backend REST API using Laravel for a web-based project called 'Butiko', which contains articles and activities carried out by the 'Butiko' community.
- Tech: PHP, Laravel, MySql, Insomnia & Git

Lab Assistant

Universitas Dipoengoro Aug 2020 - Des 2020

Fundamental of Programming Lab Assistant

• Educate and enlighten students about the fundamentals of functional programming using Python.

• Tech: Python

EDUCATION

Universitas Diponegoro

 $\begin{array}{c} {\bf Semarang,\ Jawa\ Tengah} \\ {\bf 2019 \ -\ September\ 2023\ (Expected)} \end{array}$

Majoring in **Informatics** *GPA*: 3.86 out of 4.00 Taking a specialization in software engineering

Projects

COBLOS Laravel, Bootstrap, Git

COBLOS

Contribute as the backend programmer in developing a survey web-based application that helps companies or individuals manage their surveys.

Siperpus Laravel, SailsJS, Bootstrap, Git

sisperpus | API

Give an extraordinary contribution as the backend programmer for this project and great teamwork. Siperpus is a library management system developed using Laravel.

Anforom 2021 Laravel, JavaScript, Github

Anforcom

Took charge as a backend programmer in creating, developing, and maintaining Anforcom's website, which is a competition and seminar that is held annually by the HMIF Undip.

SKILLS

Hard Skills:

 $C,\,C++,\,Rust,\,Python,\,PHP,\,JavaScript,\,SQL,\,Laravel,\,NodeJS,\,Postman,\,Heroku,\,Redis,$

RabbitMQ, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Terraform, GitLab CI/CD, Grafana,

Prometheus, CMake, Vegeta.

Soft Skills: Analytical & critical thinking, supportiveness, patience and time management.